你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第五集
格里芬竞选市长
电台信号
会话分析  语言识别
市长大位选举在即
The mayor's office is up for grabs,
市议员艾德・格里芬
and city councilman Ed Griffin
今日宣布加入角逐
threw his hat in the ring today.
新的市长候选人
New candidate for mayor,
沃克宣布参选
电台信号
会话分析  语言识别
沃克宣布参选
地方检察官助理兰登・沃克
Assistant DA Landon Walker.
沃克宣布参选
这是割喉战
This thing is a bloodbath.
市长竞选白热化
音频拦截  预付费手机
会话分析  语音识别
市长竞选白热化
音频拦截  预付费手机
会话分析  语音识别
格里芬和沃克咬得死紧
Griffin and Walker are neck and neck.
是的  我听说局势要生变了
Yeah, I hear that's about to change.
格里芬募款方式遭抨击
那名记者  玛克辛・安吉拉斯
That reporter, Maxine Angelis,
格里芬募款方式遭抨击
玛克辛・安吉拉斯
玛克辛・安吉拉斯 ---
记者
玛克辛・安吉拉斯
她说格里芬的一位募款人
she says one of Griffin's money men
一直在做假账
has been cooking the books.
获取
手机麦克风
主体：安吉拉斯  玛克辛
你是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是那个没有告诉你妻子
I'm the person who's not telling your wife
你正在酒店等妓女的人
that you're in a hotel room waiting for a hooker.
你办公室没回我电话  希克斯先生
Your office wasn't returning my calls, Mr. Hix,
因此我决定亲自前来拜访
so I thought I'd reach out to you personally.
玛克辛・安吉拉斯  《纽约日报》的
Maxine Angelis, New York Journal.
这种小把戏可是双刃剑
This little game cuts both ways.
如果你的读者发现
What will your readers think when they find out
你靠敲诈来报道  他们会怎么想
you get your stories using blackmail?
他们会想  我真称职
They'll think I'm good at my job.
接下来的五天里
In the next five days,
纽约将选出一位新市长  而我很好奇
New York elects a new mayor, and I'm very curious
你为艾德・格里芬竞选非法募款的事
about the illegal fundraising you've done for Ed Griffin's campaign.
正面回答我的问题
Give me straight answers,
我会大发善心  不提采访的所在场景
and I'll be kind enough to omit the circumstances of our interview.
你想知道什么
What is it you wanna know?
你为格里芬募款超过10万美元
You've raised over $100,000 for Griffin.
我明白玛克辛为什么总能拿到头条了
I can see why Maxine keeps making headlines.
像安吉拉斯女士这种调查记者
Investigative journalists like Ms. Angelis
现在濒临被淘汰的危险
are an endangered species.
为了跟上博客和社交媒体的节奏
In order to keep up with bloggers and social media,
专职记者不得不花样百出以获取真相
dedicated reporters have to be increasingly creative to get the truth.
芬奇  这是反馈杂音吗
Finch... is that feedback?
不是  我傻乎乎地犯了个严重错误
No, I simply made the grievous error
给小熊买了个会吱吱叫的玩具
of buying Bear a squeaky toy.
在为日报工作的六年里
In the six years she's worked at the journal,
她揭露了纽约最危险的罪犯
she's penned exposes on New York's most dangerous criminals.
毒帮  以利亚  HR
The cartel, Elias, HR.
她树了不少劲敌啊
She's made some very powerful enemies.
多半是玛克辛的某条报道害她惹上杀身之祸
Odds are one of Maxine's stories is about to get her killed.
好了  我只需要这些
Okay, I got what I need.
谢谢你抽时间见我  希克斯先生
Thank you for your time, Mr. Hix.
替我向你太太问好
And tell your wife I said hi.
玛克  记得你以为HR
Max, remember how you thought HR
还有很多黑警逍遥在外吗
had a lot more dirty cops out there?
你猜对了
You were right.
联调局起诉了几十名纽约警察
The feds are indicting dozens of NYPD officers.
我就来
On my way.
联调局  你被捕了
FBI. You're under arrest.
你们俩  下车
You two, out of the car.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
虽然抓人的是他们  但我知道功是你立的
They're making the bust, but I know this was you.
干得漂亮  警探
Nice work, Detective.
小点声成不  卡特
Keep your voice down, huh, Carter?
你以为约翰派我去HR卧底
You think John put me under with HR
是因为我记录清白吗
because of my spotless record?
真高兴联调局还没冲我来
Glad the feds haven't come after me yet.
来日方长  弗斯科
The day is still young, Fusco.
唐纳利特工  今天收获不少啊
Agent Donnelly, big day for you.
谢谢  卡特
Thanks, Carter.
还有  别以为我忘了那名"西装男"
And, don't think I've forgotten about your man in the suit.
我们一处理完这桩事  就去抓他
We will catch him as soon as we're done with this.
我看好像处理得差不多了
Looks pretty done to me.
超过75名黑警被铐了
Over 75 dirty cops in bracelets.
你怎么还毫无笑意啊
So why aren't you smiling?
没抓到幕后老大  是不是
You don't have the big boss, do you?
HR的头儿
Head of HR.
有哪个特别可疑的警察吗
So got a particular cop in mind?
我不确定他是警察
I'm not so sure it is a cop.
如果我手头的线索是真的
If the lead I'm working pans out,
很快我就能知道谁是幕后黑手了
soon I'll know exactly who was running things.
卡特
Hey, Carter.
我的建议  别管这事儿了  好吗
My two cents-- let this one go, okay?
HR坑过的每一个坏蛋
Every crook HR screwed over,
打过交道的每一个黑帮
every cartel they were in bed with,
都想要这个幕后老大的命
they're all gonna want the big boss dead.
不管谁抓到这家伙  最好做足防弹措施
Whoever catches that guy... better be bullet proof.
我反而更想抓到他了  是不是很怪
Is it weird that that just makes me wanna catch him more?
对你来说吗  不怪
For you? No.
小子  是爸爸
Hey, kiddo, it's dad.
别忘了  今天我去学校接你
Remember, I'm picking you up from school today,
别坐巴士了
so don't take the bus.
想想今晚你想看什么电影
And think about what movie you wanna watch tonight.
好吗  我稍后打给你
All right? I'll call you later.
你好啊  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
西蒙斯  我没有
Look, Simmons, I didn't...
省省你的花言巧语吧
Spare me whatever steaming pot you're about to serve up.
我看见你了
I saw you.
联调局找上HR的那天
The day the FBI got into HR,
我看到你帮西装男了
I saw you helping that guy in the suit.
知道我闪过什么念头吗
You know what even crossed my mind?
也许你就是要扳倒我们的内鬼
You might be the rat who tried to take us down.
不过你没有那么傻  没有吧  莱奈尔
But you wouldn't be that stupid, now would you, Lionel?
-没有  -那就好
- No. - Good.
HR虽然被端了  但我们还没出局
'cause HR might be down, but we are not out.
我的老大正在幕后活动
My boss is pulling strings right now
以保住高层
to save the upper management.
有那种朋友  还要我干啥
With friends like that, what do you need me for?
因为联调局不肯停手
Because the FBI keeps digging.
听说他们正在调查一条线索
We got word that they're onto something
能把我们连锅端了
that could still bring us all down.
我  我的老大  也许还有你
Me, my boss, probably even you.
什么线索
What do they got?
何不由你来告诉我
Why don't you tell me?
你的搭档和唐纳利那么铁
Your partner's all buddy-buddy with Donnelly.
所以你要去查明他们在找什么
So you're gonna find out what they're looking for,
然后销毁掉
and you're gonna make it disappear.
要是我不呢
And if I don't?
那就监狱里见吧
well, I guess I'll see you in prison.
你儿子知道你的所作所为
I mean, what's your kid gonna think
会怎么想啊
when he finds out what you did?
你觉得你前妻还会让他再和你见面吗
You think your ex-wife's even gonna let you see him again?
你跟我们一样迫切需要摆脱这些
I mean, you need this to go away as bad as we do.
到了关键时候  谁又会帮你呢
Push comes to shove, who's got your back here?
是你那位自命清高的搭档  还是我
That goody-two-shoes partner of yours or me?
就为我们做这最后一件事  莱奈尔
Just do this one thing for us, Lionel.
然后如果你想退出  就可以退出
Then if you want out, you're out.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：十九罗汉  圈圈  板栗桑  hammer_tank  大黑  天朝直属
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   擦擦   初校：NoNopig  紫玉
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监：阿好
格里芬的10万问题
市长竞选中的非法募款
沃克领先
奎恩  什么风把你从竞选总部吹到这儿了
So, Quinn, what brings you out of campaign HQ?
主要是我们老大的怒吼
My boss' screaming mostly.
你让我过了水深火热的一天呀
You've made this a very tough day for me.
当你同意为艾德・格里芬那样的骗子
Well, when you sign on as campaign manager
担任竞选经理的时候
for a crook like Ed Griffin,
就该料到会有水深火热的日子
you gotta expect a few tough days.
抱歉
Sorry.
我会挺过去
I'll survive.
流水的政客  铁打的你我
Politicians come and go, but you and I are here forever.
是吧  玛克
Right, Max?
私下跟你说
Off the record,
格里芬今年没戏了
it's not Griffin's year.
沃克领先  我找不到把柄可用
Walker's ahead, and I can't find any dirt to save my life.
得了吧  表面越是干净
Come on, the cleaner they are on the outside,
只要深查下去  私底越是腐败
the more rotten they are once you crack them open.
其实我就是来提醒你的
I actually came by just to warn you.
格里芬想整你以立威
Griffin wants your head on a pike.
告诉他排队等着
Well, tell him to get in line.
你听到了吗  芬奇
You hear that, Finch?
艾德华・格里芬  我们的最新嫌疑人
Edward Griffin, our newest suspect
但可能不是最后一个
but likely not our last.
小熊  拜托
Oh, Bear, please.
看  你的球噢
Look, here's your ball.
我应该很快就能进入玛克辛的云储存站点了
I should have access to Maxine's cloud storage site shortly.
一旦进去
Once I get inside,
我会查看她现在正在做的所有工作
I'll scan through everything she's working on,
看看还有谁想要她命
see who else might want her dead.
这不是什么新闻报道  格伦
That's not the real story, Glen.
当然不是  拷了75名警察  这是新闻消息
The hell it's not. 75 cops in cuffs--that's news.
新闻报道不是抓到了谁
The story's not who they busted,
而是没抓到谁
it's who they didn't.
HR的头儿
The head of HR.
联调局知道自己没抓住幕后老大
The FBI knows they don't have the big boss.
现在他们只是四处撒网能抓就抓
And now they're just scooping up everybody,
希望如果网撒得够大就能抓住他
hoping they'll catch him if they cast a wide enough net.
想写幕后老大吗  那好
Wanna write about the big boss? Fine.
找出是谁  找到证据
Get me a name and something to back it up.
否则  不能刊登
Until then, there's nothing to print.
这么说她是在调查HR的头儿
So she's looking for the head of HR.
我们要查查西蒙斯吗
Should we be looking at Simmons?
我分析了弗斯科警探提供的证据
Actually, my analysis of the evidence from Detective Fusco
其实西蒙斯只是个高级指挥罢了
suggests that Simmons is just a high-ranking lieutenant.
那真正话事的是谁
Then who's really in charge?
有人给玛克辛打电话
Someone's dialing Maxine's cell.
号码屏蔽了  身份不明
Number blocked, no ID.
玛克辛・安吉拉斯
Maxine Angelis.
我不能告诉你我的名字
I can't tell you my name,
但是我有你想要的信息
but I have information you want.
好吧  那是什么
Okay, what is that exactly?
HR的幕后老大  我知道是谁
HR's big boss-- I know who it is
好的  我在听
All right, I'm listening.
HR的头儿是克里斯多夫・桑布拉诺
The head of HR is Christopher Zambrano.
警方今晚就要逮捕他了
They're arresting him tonight.
-你是谁  -一位朋友
- Who is this?  - A friend.
黑头党头目嫌疑人维托利奥・桑布拉诺
与警方对峙中枪
克里斯多夫・桑布拉诺  前黑手党头目之子
Christopher Zambrano, son of the late mafia Don,
那位头目你应该还记得
whom I'm sure you will remember.
上一季第十九集中的号码之一
但与其父不同
But unlike his father,
克里斯多夫似乎很清白
Christopher seems to have kept his nose clean.
这就更方便他
Which would make him
在黑帮和警察之间居中联络
a good liaison between the mob and the police.
他自己有一家进出口公司
He owns an import-export business.
走私活动的绝佳伪装
Perfect cover for the kind of smuggling operations
方便HR大发横财
that have lined HR's pockets.
现在她给联调局的线人打电话了
And now she's calling one of her contacts in the FBI.
-克拉克特工  -威利斯
- Agent Clark.  - Willis.
我是玛克辛・安吉拉斯
Maxine Angelis.
是否还记得  上次你指挥突袭冰毒实验室
So remember when you led that meth lab raid
结果不小心闯错了房间
and accidentally busted into the wrong house,
我在报道中隐去了你的名字
and I left your name out of the paper,
你说不知道该怎么谢我
and you said you didn't know how to thank me?
我刚刚帮你想到了
Well, I just thought of a way.
你想要什么  玛克辛
What do you want, Maxine?
关于HR的调查你知道些什么
What do you know about the HR investigation?
我收到消息说克里斯多夫・桑布拉诺
I just got a tip that Christopher Zambrano
是运作全局的老大
is the boss of the whole operation.
好吧  这事的背景实在太深
Okay, this is deep, deep background.
不过  是的
But, uh, yeah,
我知道他们正在调查他和HR的关系
I know they're looking at him in connection with HR.
唐纳利准备起诉书的时候
And when Donnelly was putting in paperwork for the indictments,
我听到他多次提及桑布拉诺
I heard him talking about Zambrano a lot.
好的  谢谢  威利斯
Okay. Well, thanks, Willis.
我仍会在报道中隐去你的名字
I'll keep your name out of this story too.
她好像真的查出东西来了
Sounds like she's really onto something.
我们必须要调查一下桑布拉诺了
We definitely need to check out Zambrano.
我想玛克辛抢我前边了
I think Maxine might beat me to it.
桑布拉诺先生
Mr. Zambrano.
玛克辛・安吉拉斯  《纽约日报》的
Maxine Angelis, New York Journal.
幸会  滚出我的地盘
Nice to meet you. Get off my property.
为什么  有什么不能让记者知道的吗
Why? Do you have something to hide from a reporter?
克里斯多夫・桑布拉诺
强制配对
完成
可以监视监听桑布拉诺了  芬奇
Got eyes and ears on Zambrano, Finch.
尽管调查吧
Search all you want.
全都是进口家具
All you're gonna find is imported furniture,
旋转木马部件  是我买来做慈善的
parts of a kiddie carousel, which I bought for charity.
这能上报纸吗  不能
Does that make it into the papers? No.
因为我姓桑布拉诺
Because my last name is Zambrano,
所以你们都觉得我是黑手党
you guys all think I'm a wise guy.
不  我觉得你是HR的头儿
No, I think you're the head of HR.
你到底在说什么  谁告诉你的
What the hell are you talking about? Who told you that?
我觉得你很清楚我在说什么
I think you know exactly what I'm talking about.
你最近见过唐纳利特工吗
Did you get a visit recently from Agent Donnelly?
从未见过他
Never seen him before.
有意思  门卫看到他来过这里
Funny, 'cause the guard at the gate has seen him here,
还和你争吵
arguing with you.
黑手党头目之子
Son of a mafia Don,
进出口公司老板
owner of an import-export business,
被联邦调查局特工因HR事件盘问
getting grilled by the FBI agent hunting HR.
如果你未牵连其中  那要如何解释呢
So if you're not involved, then how would you explain that?
给我闭嘴
Shut your mouth.
我什么都不知道  好吗
I don't know anything about that, okay?
如果你再继续这样问问题
And if you keep on asking questions like this,
会害死人
somebody's gonna get hurt.
这样不行  芬奇  我要过去
I don't like this, Finch. I'm going in.
里瑟  不能过去  玛克辛还在做另一个调查
Reese, you can't. Maxine has another pet story.
她一直在研究警局记录
She's been scouring through police records,
走访目击证人
talking to witnesses,
找一名西装男
hunting for a man in a suit...
就是你
meaning you.
我们是通过秘密政府机器
We're fugitives getting illegal information
获取非法信息的逃亡者
from a secret government machine.
约翰  我们绝对不能公开
John, the last thing we need is publicity.
你要保护安吉拉斯女士
You must protect Ms. Angelis,
但与此同时  还不能让她拿到
but you have to do it without giving her any more proof
西装男存在的证据
that the man in the suit exists.
你以为我会相信
Do you expect me to believe
你敢在你做合法生意的地盘上对我动手
you're gonna lay a finger on me at your legitimate business?
-不准刊登  -桑布拉诺先生
- You don't print that.  - Mr. Zambrano.
不准写这种文章
You don't write that.
"HR老大嫌疑人袭击记者"
"Suspected HR boss assaults reporter."
你觉得这种标题会减轻你的嫌疑吗
Do you think that headline makes you look less guilty?
泰迪  送这娘们离开我的地盘
Hey, Teddy, escort this bitch off my property.
好吧  芬奇
Okay, Finch.
我要怎样才能救一名
How am I supposed to save a woman
想把我变成头条新闻的女人呢
who wants to put me on the front page?
虽然情况很复杂
Despite this complication,
我们仍必须确保玛克辛的安全
we must focus on keeping Maxine safe.
从桑布拉诺的网络数据资料中
I can't find anything in Zambrano's digital footprint
看不出他是HR的头儿
to suggest that he's the head of HR,
不过我们也曾被聪明的罪犯骗过
but brilliant criminals have fooled us before.
我非常希望你不要在这里弄这个
I do wish you wouldn't do that here.
在公园弄这个  人家看我的眼神好古怪
When I do it in the park, people look at me funny.
好吧  先假设桑布拉诺是HR的头儿
Okay, let's assume that Zambrano is the head of HR.
他可能想杀掉玛克辛
He might want to have Maxine killed
以免真实身份被她报道曝光
before she can reveal his true identity in the paper.
这也太难了
It would be damn hard
又要阻止他们  还不能让玛克辛看到我
to stop them if I can't let Maxine see me work.
可如果你从天而降英雄救美
And when you step out of the shadows to help her out,
她会知道你就是那个西装男
she's going to know you're the man in the suit.
在想到方法让你光明正大出现之前
Until we can figure out a way to hide you in plain sight,
或许你该先寻求下支援了
perhaps you should enlist some backup.
玛克辛・安吉拉斯  对  我听说过她
Maxine Angelis. Yeah, I've heard of her.
那女人向来刨根问底
That woman leaves no stone unturned.
你在她身边怎么大显神通
How do you expect to work your magic with her around?
你跟你的朋友不是死乞白赖
Aren't you and your friend obsessed
不肯曝光吗
with staying out of the paper?
我会保持距离
I'll keep my distance.
我发的另一张照片是克里斯・桑布拉诺
The other photo I sent you is Chris Zambrano.
玛克辛觉得他是HR的幕后老大
Maxine thinks he's HR's big boss.
这么说他跟他爸一样坏
So he's crooked like his dad, huh?
你没事吧  弗斯科
Everything okay, Fusco?
没事
Yeah.
就是  有点吃坏肚子了
It's, uh... something I ate probably.
HR的头儿绝不是什么简单的人物
Yeah, well, you don't become head of HR by being sloppy.
如果桑布拉诺想弄死这个记者
So if Zambrano wants your reporter dead,
他下手肯定会悄无声息
he'll do it in a way that's practically invisible
毫无痕迹
with no strings leading back to him.
弗斯科  你最后一次
Fusco, when's the last time
见西蒙斯是什么时候
you saw your pal Simmons?
上次我为救你朝他开枪之后  就再没见他了
We haven't talked since I shot at him, covering your ass.
找到他  跟踪他
Find him. Tail him.
如果他找你麻烦
And if he gives you any trouble,
我会帮你
I've got your back.
我会跟唐纳利谈谈
I'll talk to Donnelly,
看看HR的贿赂名单中
see who else is on HR's payroll
还有谁没被抓
that hasn't been arrested yet.
如果那位记者在我们找到杀手前
And if your reporter friend gets into trouble
就遇到了麻烦
before we find the shooter--
估计我就只能报警了
Guess I'll have to call the police.
即时新闻
募款门：格里芬放弃钱
虽然我未觉察到任何不端行为
And though I'm unaware of any wrong-doing,
仍会将受质疑资金捐给慈善事业
the funds in question will be donated to charity.
以上是艾德・格里芬就《纽约日报》
That's Ed Griffin issuing a statement
对自己的指控所做出的回应
about allegations in the New York Journal.
兰登・沃克在我们的演播室
Landon Walker is in our studio.
沃克先生  您有何评论
Mr. Walker, your response.
要知道  鲍伯
You see, Bob,
隐匿证据并不能改变犯罪的事实
hiding the evidence doesn't erase the crime.
我的竞选对手显然不懂这点
This is what my opponent doesn't get.
瞧她挑起的
Look at what she started.
如果我当选  会推动本市再现诚实与廉正
If I'm elected, I'll bring honesty and integrity back to the city.
下面从政治新闻转到天气预报
Turning our attention from politics to the weather--
我找到了  格伦  HR的头儿
I got him, Glen, the head of HR.
克里斯托弗・桑布拉诺
Christopher Zambrano.
黑手党头目的儿子  有什么证据
The mafia Don's kid? Based on what?
四个情报来源  匿名消息
Four sources, anonymous tip,
码头警卫
guard at the docks,
一名熟悉案件的联调局探员
an FBI agent familiar with the case,
以及桑布拉诺本人
and Zambrano himself.
他向你承认了吗
He admitted it to you?
他总不会是因为清白无辜才冲我大吼大叫吧
I don't think he was yelling at me 'cause he's innocent.
听说唐纳利已经写好起诉书了
I hear Donnelly's already filed the indictment.
我们在网站上公布消息
We'll run it on the website...
等联调局抓他之后再进行编辑
and back-edit it once the feds pick him up.
桑布拉诺  HR老大嫌疑人即将被捕
秘密曝光了
Well, the cat's out of the bag,
但安吉拉斯女士还是没有脱离危险
but Ms. Angelis is not out of danger yet.
桑布拉诺可能会为报仇下令杀死她
Zambrano may order her execution for simple revenge.
他不进监狱  她就不可能脱离危险
She's not safe until he's behind bars.
芬奇  这样子我没法保护她
Finch, I can't protect her like this.
我必须接近她
I've got to get close to her.
你马上就可以了
You're about to.
玛克辛的工作没给她多少机会
It seems that Maxine's job doesn't afford her opportunities
去认识好男人
to meet nice men,
因此她只好不情愿地
so she somewhat reluctantly
注册了一个人气约会网站
signed up with a popular online dating site.
我黑进了这个网站
I took the liberty of back-engineering
根据后台匹配算法创建了
the matching algorithm to create the profile
她梦中情人的档案
of her ideal man.
她很欣赏你爱狗这一点
She really likes that you love dogs.
等等
Wait.
你想让我跟她约会
You're trying to get me a date with her?
已经约好了  今天晚上八点
Already have. Tonight at 8:00.
你们已经调情一整天了
You've been flirting all day.
芬奇  我刚刚跟她说了什么
Finch? What did I just say to her?
买新袖扣也就算了
New cufflinks I could understand,
居然还买了辆十万美元的跑车
but buying a $100,000 sports car--
真的有必要吗
was that really necessary?
放松  芬奇  车是偷的
Relax, Finch. The car's stolen.
车不错
Nice car.
希望这不是什么心理补偿的需要
Let's hope you're not compensating for something.
记着  你名叫约翰・安德森
Remember, your name is John Anderson...
詹森精算公司的副总裁
VP at Jenson Actuarial.
你喜欢遛狗  划皮艇
You like walking your dog, kayaking,
希区柯克的电影
and Hitchcock movies.
还有  玛克辛喜欢知识分子
And Maxine's fondness for intellectuals
我们正好可以优雅地伪装你的身份
presents us with a graceful way to help cover up your identity.
我给你买的眼镜你戴了吧
Are you wearing those glasses I got you?
-请坐  -当然
- Here you are. - Sure.
晚餐愉快
Enjoy.
我
I, uh--
我提前打电话来点了这瓶酒
I called ahead and ordered us a bottle.
希望你喜欢喝香槟
Hope you like champagne.
我不喜欢
I don't.
你不记得我们在线聊天时还开过这个玩笑吗
Don't you remember joking about this online?
抱歉  麻烦请来一杯花花公子
Sorry, um, can I get a boulevardier, please?
你没看我发给你的注意事项吗
Did you not review the notes I sent you?
那么  约翰
So, John...
我一直都很好奇
I've always wondered.
精算到底是干什么的
What does an actuarial actually do?
大部分时间在昏昏欲睡
Most days, just try to stay awake.
里瑟先生  回答错误
Mr. Reese. Wrong answer!
玛克辛热爱自己的职业
Maxine is passionate about her career,
她想要伴侣也是如此
and she wants a partner who feels the same way.
好吧  该派增援了
Okay, time for reinforcements.
约翰
John.
近来如何
How are you?
佐伊
Zoe.
你想让我吃醋吗
You trying to make me jealous?
芬奇让你待命
Finch have you on standby?
社会心理学
Social psychology.
女性更青睐于
Women are more attracted to men
受到魅力女性认可的男性
who receive the approval of other attractive women.
玛克辛  这是佐伊
Maxine, this is Zoe.
她是我的朋友
She's a friend.
你们是怎么认识的
So how do you two know each other?
去年我们共同度过了两晚的漫漫长夜
Oh, we spent two very long nights together last year.
真高兴再见到你  约翰
It was great seeing you again, John.
谢谢
Thanks.
你跟佐伊・摩根约会过
You dated Zoe Morgan?
整个城市的记者
There's not a reporter in town
都拼死想要采访那女人
who wouldn't kill to interview that woman.
科学啊
Science.
社会心理学的原则就在于其
The tenets of social psychology are firmly rooted in an unders--
说说你的工作吧
So tell me about your job.
现在手头最刺激的新闻是什么
What's the most exciting story you're working on right now?
你会觉得我很怪
Oh, you'll just think I'm weird.
好吧  传说有一个人
Okay, well, there's a rumor about this guy,
警方一直称他为"西装男"
the police just call him the man in a suit.
无人见过他的容貌  无人知道他的名字
No one's seen his face, no one knows his name.
我甚至不确定他是否存在
I'm not even sure he exists.
可他就像漫画中的角色一样
But he's like something out of a comic book.
人们遇到麻烦时  他就会从天而降
When people are in trouble, he comes out of nowhere.
他似乎总会及时出现
He always seems to be there just in time.
不管他是谁  他救了很多人的性命
And whoever he is, he saves a lot of lives.
也射穿了很多人的膝盖
And he shoots a lot of kneecaps.
听上去是个很棒的家伙
Sounds like a great guy,
一个都市传奇
and an urban legend.
是啊  也许  但如果他真的存在
Yeah, well, maybe. But if he's real...
我就要把他刊登在
I'm going to put that man on the cover
全国每份报纸和杂志的封面上
of every magazine and newspaper in this country.
克里斯多夫・桑布拉诺呢
What about Christopher Zambrano?
我看了你的网站
I read your website.
有没有担心过报道那种人会
Ever worry that writing about a man like that might
让你身处险境
put you in harm's way?
职业风险嘛
Occupational hazard.
其实不如趁机周末出城放松一下
Still couldn't hurt to skip town for the weekend,
等事情平息
let this blow over.
感谢你的关心  约翰
Oh, thanks for your concern, John,
也感谢你约我出城的狡猾手段
and for that very slick offer to whisk me away.
不过  这是我的工作
But, you know, this is what I do.
我挖掘人们想知道的东西
I find out what people need to know,
当权者想隐瞒的东西
what those in power don't want them to know,
确保所有人都能知情
and I make sure everyone hears about it.
对我来说  这值得冒点险
To me, that's worth a little risk.
"在普天下皆骗的时代
"In times of universal deceit,
讲真话就是一种革命行为"
telling the truth is a revolutionary act."
乔治・奥威尔
George Orwell.
不好意思
You know what, I'm sorry.
我得接个电话  抱歉
I have to take this. Sorry.
格伦  好的  格伦  格伦  格伦
Glen. Okay, Glen, Glen, Glen.
慢点说  慢点说
Slow down, slow down!
-现在不太方便  卡特  -有麻烦了
- Kind of busy, Carter. - We have a problem.
我刚和唐纳利打完电话
I just got off the phone with Donnelly, and...
玛克辛关于桑布拉诺是HR幕后老大的报道
Maxine's story about Zambrano being the big boss of HR--
桑布拉诺  HR老大嫌疑人即将被捕
不是真的
It's not true.
天哪  好吧
Oh, my God. Oka--
天呐
Oh, my God.
桑布拉诺不是老大
Zambrano's not the boss?
他甚至不是嫌疑人
He isn't even a suspect.
但她写了那份报道
But then she wrote that thing,
害他成为众矢之的
she put a bull's-eye on his chest.
HR坑过的每一个坏蛋
Every crook HR screwed,
合作过的每一个黑帮
every cartel they worked with,
每个人都想要他的命
everyone wants him dead.
玛克辛没有危险  桑布拉诺才有
Maxine's not in danger, Zambrano is.
我们得赶紧找到他  否则就晚了
We need to find him before it's too late.
你错了  玛克  联调局已经在路上了
You're wrong, Max. The FBI's on their way.
-他们要和你谈谈  -好的
- They wanna talk to you. - Okay, all right.
先别管我  桑布拉诺在哪
Forget about me. Where is Zambrano?
-他还好吗  -他的手机无人接听
- And is he okay? - He's not answering his cell.
没人知道他在哪
No one knows where he is.
紧急情况  再联系
Work emergency. I'll call you.
好吧  我不知道你的紧急情况如何
Okay, well, I don't know what your work emergency is,
但我肯定我的更紧急
but I bet mine's worse.
我害桑布拉诺身处险境
I just put Zambrano's life in danger,
需要你送我一程
so I need you to give me a ride.
好了  在车里等着
Okay, wait in the car.
你很接近了  里瑟先生
You're close, Mr. Reese.
桑布拉诺在你西北方300米的地方
Zambrano is 300 meters west-northwest of you.
估计联调局没监控他的手机
Guess the FBI doesn't have him bluejacked.
桑布拉诺先生
Mr. Zambrano!
克里斯
Chris!
桑布拉诺在哪
Where's Zambrano?
救命
Help!
芬奇
Finch.
我们来晚了
We didn't get here in time.
安吉拉斯女士  安德森先生  是吗
Okay, Ms. Angelis. And Mr. Anderson, was it?
你可以叫我约翰
You can call me John.
我只需要录个口供
I just need to get a statement.
你发现的桑布拉诺先生  对吗
You found Mr. Zambrano, right?
他中枪了
He was shot,
没有呼吸了
and he wasn't breathing.
都是我的错
It was all my fault.
对不起  我能不能  我需要喘口气
I'm sorry, can I-- I just need a minute.
好的  没问题
Yeah, sure.
你和她约会
You're dating her?
你就是如此"保持距离"的吗
That's how you're keeping your distance?
这个  有点复杂
It's, um... complicated.
凶手在现场被我打晕了
Your killers are knocked out at the scene.
我猜他们是斗牛士帮的
My guess is they're Toreros Cartel.
那些想要HR老大命的众多帮派之一
Just one of many organizations that wanted HR's boss dead.
可惜杀错了人
Just got the wrong guy.
我留在这里太不合适了
Look, this isn't the best place for me to be,
但我不能丢下她
but I'm not leaving her.
我能把她带走吗
Can I get her out of here?
好吧
Yeah.
来吧  她说我们能走了
Come on. She said we could go.
另类的第一次约会啊
Some first date, huh?
玛克辛・安吉拉斯
Maxine Angelis.
我是唐纳利特工  联调局的
Special Agent Donnelly, FBI.
你得回答一些问题
You're gonna answer some questions.
门卫告诉我
The gate guard told me
你曾和桑布拉诺有过争吵
that you'd been arguing with Zambrano,
而且我和一名特工谈过
and an agent I spoke to--
克拉克特工一无所知
Agent Clark didn't know anything,
不过我完全没兴趣
but I am really not interested
听你为自己的行为进行辩解
in hearing you try to justify what you did.
我只想知道是谁第一个告诉你
All I want is the name of the person who first told you
克里斯・桑布拉诺是HR的头儿
that Chris Zambrano was the head of HR.
我接到一个电话  是匿名消息
I got a call. It was an anonymous tip.
是个男的  号码屏蔽了
It was a man. Blocked number.
11:41  是这个
11:41. That's it.
但如果他不是老大  那你为什么
But if he wasn't the boss, then why were you even--
你究竟知不知道
Do you have any idea how
你捅了多大的篓子
colossally you just screwed up?
桑布拉诺不是HR的老大
Zambrano wasn't HR's boss.
他是能够扳倒老大的证人
He was the witness that could bring the boss down.
桑布拉诺的父亲是HR在黑帮的核心人物
Zambrano's father was the mob's point man with HR.
他做了记录  有一个账本
And he kept records-- a ledger--
记录了HR的贿赂名单及贿赂金额
with names and dollar amounts for everyone on HR's payroll,
包括老大
including the boss.
黑帮头目死后
And when the Don died,
克里斯・桑布拉诺发现了账本
Chris Zambrano found that ledger.
但与他爸爸不同  克里斯是好人
But unlike his dad, Chris was a good man.
清清白白
Totally clean.
当他意识到自己拿的是什么
When he realized what he was holding,
他联系了联调局
he called the FBI.
为什么你不保护他
Why didn't you protect him?
你以为我们在争吵什么
What do you think we were arguing about?
我试着说服他
I tried to convince him.
但就因为你这种人
But because of people like you
总是视他为罪犯
calling him a criminal all his life,
桑布拉诺害怕我们也会认为他不干净
Zambrano was afraid that we would think he was dirty too.
他要求拿到豁免后  才交出账本
He'd only turn over the ledger once he'd sign an immunity deal,
相关文件今晚才送到
and the paperwork came through tonight.
如果你敢报道一个字
And if you print one word of this,
我就以妨碍公务罪把你关起来
I will lock your ass up for obstruction.
你的消息来自一次性手机
Well, your tip came from a disposable cell,
罪犯的首选
the first choice of criminals
几乎不可能被追查到
and virtually impossible to trace.
所以恭喜你  安吉拉斯女士
So congratulations, Ms. Angelis,
你被耍了
you just got played,
多半是被真正的HR头儿耍了
probably by the real head of HR.
这么说玛克辛不是受害人  而是行凶者
So Maxine wasn't the victim. She was the perpetrator.
无意间的  非自愿的
Unwitting, involuntary,
但仍然是行凶者
but a perpetrator all the same.
一石二鸟
With one stroke,
老大解决了唯一能扳倒他的证人
the boss wipes out the only witness who could bring him down.
还毁了一名麻烦记者的职业生涯
And destroys the career of a troublesome reporter to boot.
我们要找出那个王八蛋
And we're gonna find out who that bastard is
扳倒他
and bring him down.
我来查一下桑布拉诺的网络数据资料
And I'll search Zambrano's digital footprint,
看看能不能找到他把那本写有老大名字的账本
see if I can find out where he hid the ledger
藏在哪里了
with the boss' name in it.
那我看看我们的卧底能挖出点什么
And I'll see what our undercover can dig up.
弗斯科  你得和西蒙斯谈谈
Fusco, you and Simmons need to have a little talk.
探探他是否知道HR真正的头儿是谁
See if he knows who the real head of HR is.
不  如果西蒙斯知道
Nah, if Simmons knew that,
我们搞掉HR的时候我就抓到老大了
I would have brought down the boss when we took down HR.
还是问问吧  有发现及时告诉我
Well, ask anyway, and let me know if you find anything out.
好吧  老大
Will do, boss.
好吧  桑布拉诺  你到底把账本藏哪了
All right, Zambrano, where did you hide that ledger?
玛克辛・安吉拉斯
Maxine Angelis.
玛克吗  我是奎恩  你怎么样了
Max? Quinn. How are you?
看来是轮到我水深火热了
Guess I was due for a tough day.
是啊  我们接下来会利用此事贬低你的可信度
Yeah, look, we're gonna have use this thing to discredit you,
以及你写的格里芬报道的可信度
everything you wrote about Griffin.
要把你往火坑里推了  玛克
We're throwing you under the bus, Max.
抱歉
Sorry.
你是真正的朋友  奎恩
You're a true friend, Quinn.
格伦
Glen.
我能做点什么吗
What can I do?
我们已经解决了
I think we've got it handled.
我们准备把A1版上的选举文章
We're moving the election off A-1
替换成为桑布拉诺澄清的文章
to make room for our retraction on Zambrano.
我可以写澄清的文章
I can write the retraction.
恐怕你不能再写任何东西了
I'm afraid you won't be writing anything
要等我们跟律师谈过后再说
until we sit down with legal.
安吉拉斯女士的记者生涯虽然前途未卜
Ms. Angelis' future as a journalist may be in doubt,
但她还是没停止调查
but she's not done investigating.
她正打给那个一次性手机
She's calling that disposable cell.
您已转接入
You have reached a voice mail box
尚未设置的语音信箱
that has not been set up yet.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are,
但我知道你做了什么  也知道如何查到你
but I know what you did, and I know where to find your name.
一旦让我查到
And when I do,
我会把你带着手铐的照片
I will put a picture of you in handcuffs
登在报纸的头版头条上
on the front page of this paper.
她要去找HR的账本
She's looking for that HR ledger.
我得阻止她
Then I need to get her to stop
惹上麻烦
before she gets herself in trouble.
-你好  -玛克辛  我是约翰
- Hello? - Maxine, it's John.
不知可否约你出来喝一杯
I thought maybe you could use a drink.
接到你的电话我很惊喜
I was surprised to hear from you.
第一次约会就遇着谋杀
There's generally no second date
一般不会再有第二次了
when the first one ends in homicide.
我  一直想你
Well, I was, um... thinking about you,
想看看我能否能帮上忙
and I wanted to see if I could help.
既然你主动提出来
Well, now that you mention it,
我想借你专业的会计眼光
I could use your accounting skills
帮我看一下这些记录
to just go through these records.
这是我能找到的桑布拉诺的所有资料
Here's everything I've got on Zambrano.
我们在找桑布拉诺可能藏
We're looking for anywhere Zambrano might've--
我觉得我们应该把这些事情
I think maybe we should just leave that
交给有关部门处理
for the proper authorities.
我把独家新闻看得重于事实真相
I put getting the scoop before getting the truth.
我的自负害死了一个好人
And my arrogance cost a good man his life.
现在我  我做什么都无法弥补了
Now I can't--I can't do anything to fix that.
但我一定会抓住那个幕后的王八蛋
But I sure as hell can catch the bastard behind all of this.
谢谢你的啤酒
Thanks for the beer.
玛克辛  玛克辛
Maxine. Maxine!
我了解那种无法挽回的感受
I know how it feels to do things you can never take back.
我无法平复你的伤痛  阻止你去弥补
I can't stop you from hurting or wanting to fix this.
但我不想让你以为自己是一个人
But I just don't want you to think you're alone.
趴下
Get down!
芬奇  我想那老大收到玛克辛的信息了
Finch, I think the boss got Maxine's message.
钥匙给我
Give me your keys.
芬奇  我们现在去我家
Finch, we're heading to my place.
糟了  你的狗在我这里
Oh, shoot! I've got your dog.
小熊比照片上还可爱
Bear's even cuter than his picture.
他很喜欢那个柜子嘛
He really likes that closet, huh?
他的  宝贝在里面
His, uh, treats are in there.
刚才真是精彩
So...that was interesting.
也许我们应该报警
Maybe we should call the cops.
报哪个警
Which ones?
HR的老大还逍遥在外
If HR's boss is still out there,
我不知道能相信谁
I don't know who to trust.
你知道是谁向我们开枪吗
Any idea who was shooting at us?
不知道  但既然他们想杀我
No, but if they're trying to kill me,
我肯定是做对了什么事
I must be doing something right.
看来你的无聊工作收入不菲啊
Guess your boring job pays all right.
我明天请病假
I'm calling in sick tomorrow.
这件事结束前我不会把你丢下的
I won't leave your side until this is over.
你是好男人  约翰・安德森
You're a good man, John Anderson.
我今晚睡沙发
I'll sleep on the couch.
如我所言  好男人啊
Like I said, a good man.
我想摘一下隐形眼镜
And if I wanna take my contacts out?
那边
That way.
你几时会需要那么些东西
When were you ever going to need all those?
你不该把她带到这里来  里瑟先生
You shouldn't have brought her back here, Mr. Reese.
再好的伪装也禁不起推敲
Even the best cover just goes so deep.
她待得越久  疑问就会越多
The longer she stays, the more questions she'll have.
想想她走出来看到你
Imagine how many questions she'll have
会产生多少疑问吧
if she comes out and sees you here.
你看清开枪打你们的人的模样了吗
Did you get a good look at the men that were shooting at you?
我尽力了  但他们在开枪打我呀
I tried, but they were shooting at me.
我会黑进酒吧的监控录像
I'll get into the pub's security system
看看能查到什么
and see what I can find.
我找到一条线索  里瑟先生
I've got a lead, Mr. Reese.
我从酒吧的监控录像里找到了枪手的照片
I got images of the shooters from the pub's security.
然后找到了一个照片共享网站
Then I found a photo sharing site
里边有面部识别软件
that had a facial recognition app
这软件去年因为一起诉讼关闭
that was shut down by a lawsuit last year.
我黑了进去  从后台打开了软件
I hacked in, turned the app back on,
并确认了枪手身份
and identified our gunmen.
他们是联调局的
They're FBI.
前联调局的
Ex-FBI.
博格尔特工和皮特特工
Agents Bogle and Pitt.
他们去年提前退休了
They took early retirement last year.
但如果他们在局里还有关系
But if they've still got contacts at the bureau,
我猜就是他们告诉HR老大
I'd guess that they're the ones that told HR's boss
桑布拉诺账本的事
about Zambrano's ledger.
芬奇  我知道你想要我保持伪装
Finch, I know you want me to keep my cover,
但玛克辛需要知道她在跟什么人打交道
but Maxine needs to know what she's dealing with,
而我需要有能力保护她
and I need to be able to protect her.
冷静  约翰
Calm down, John.
我给你的女朋友发了同样内容的短信
I sent your girlfriend a text with the same information,
当然是匿名的
anonymously of course.
我需要和你一位朋友谈谈
I need to talk to a friend of yours.
伦纳德・皮特和克莱格・博格尔
Leonard Pitt and Craig Bogle,
因被控骚扰和诬告而被开除
forced out for harassment and malicious prosecution.
传言说他们被人掌控了
Word is that they were in someone's pocket.
利用职务之便为自己真正的老大卖命
They were using those badges to do favors for their real boss.
那个用一次性手机
The man who got Zambrano killed
打一个电话就害死了桑布拉诺的人
with one call from a disposable cell,
HR的头儿  他到底是谁
the head of HR-- who is he?
有些秘密即使是我也不知道
There's some secrets that even I don't know.
但你知道谁会买一次性手机
But you know who buys disposables by the case--
罪犯  当然了
Criminals, sure.
政治竞选也会
But also political campaigns.
便宜  无法追查  匿名
They're cheap, untraceable, anonymous.
一旦他们的肮脏行为被抓住
And if they get caught playing dirty tricks,
这些可以救命
it can save their ass.
我们希望我们的城市
Is this the kind of experience
虚伪
欺诈
可悲
由这种人掌管吗
we want running our city?
兰登・沃克才是负责任的
Landon Walker is the responsible,
兰登・沃克
明智之选
可靠的市长人选
reliable choice for mayor.
桑布拉诺因为知道HR老大的名字被杀
Zambrano gets killed for knowing the name of HR's boss
正好在选举前五天
five days before an election.
你的意思是那个老大在竞选市长
Are you telling me the boss is running for mayor?
我只是提出个观点
I'm rendering an opinion.
个人而言  我会避开政客
Personally, I avoid politicians.
他们基本上没什么实权
They so rarely have any real power.
很高兴见到你
You know, it's a pleasure meeting you.
但很遗憾  我们从未见过面
But it's a shame we never met.
乖  约翰
Be good, John.
是的  好  非常好  非常感谢
Yes. Okay, perfect. Thank you so much.
格里芬的一个老对手刚才证实了
One of Griffin's old opponents just confirmed
在竞选期间曾被博格尔和皮特骚扰过
being harassed by Bogle and Pitt during their campaign.
既然格里芬的支持率在上升
If Griffin's higher than before,
他们可能还在为他卖命
they're probably still working for him.
这些足够你在头版揭露他吗
Do you have enough to unmask him on the front page?
我绝不会再犯同样的错误了
I will never make that mistake again.
除非拿到账本  否则我不会再刊登
I am not going to press until I have that ledger in my hands.
我们只需要找出桑布拉诺把它藏在哪里
We just need to find where Zambrano hid it.
顺便说一句  顺利骗到我第三次约会了
Pretty smooth conning me into a third date, by the way.
我更愿意视之为首次约会的第三次尝试
I like to think of it as a third attempt at a first date.
等等
Wait. Wait.
桑布拉诺说所有人都觉得他是黑手党
Zambrano said that everybody thought he was a wise guy,
没人会看他做的善事
and nobody ever looked at the good things he did.
如果他要找个地方藏账本
If he were looking for a place to hide that ledger,
也许会藏到一个他认为
maybe he would put it where he thought
没人会看的地方
no one would go looking.
你那辆靓车上有撬棍吗
Does that fancy car of yours have a crowbar?
这里  门没锁
Here. It's unlocked.
先从马找起
Start with the horses.
它们昨天刚被运来
They were still being delivered yesterday.
找到了
Found something.
桑布拉诺的账本
Zambrano's ledger.
想知道是谁在管理HR吗
Wanna find out who's running HR?
多谢了  玛克辛
Thanks, Maxine.
我们老大找得好苦
My boss has been looking all over for that.
我已经通知了卡特警探
I've called Detective Carter,
救援就快到了  里瑟先生
and help is on the way, Mr. Reese.
我知道这有违你的本性
I know it goes against your nature,
但一采取行动
but you can't take action
玛克辛就会知道你的真实身份
without Maxine learning who you really are.
在尽可能的情况下  等待救援
If at all possible, wait for rescue.
我会尽量记着
I'll try to keep that in mind.
我得说  玛克辛  你可帮了个大忙
I gotta tell you, Maxine, you've been a huge help.
先是桑布拉诺  然后是账本
First Zambrano, then the ledger,
现在你又好心地带上了你的男朋友
and now you're kind enough to bring your boyfriend.
我只要把你们俩扔回你家
I'm just gonna dump the two of you at your place.
布置成
We'll make it look like
恋人吵架升级为杀人后自杀
a lover's spat turned murder-suicide.
我死了
When I wind up dead,
你以为警察不会发现我的笔记上有你的名字吗
you think the police won't find your names in my notes,
博格尔特工
Agent Bogle?
还是应该叫博格尔先生
Or is it Mr. Bogle now?
现在你不惜双重谋杀来封我的口
And now you're doing a double homicide to shut me up.
等你被捕后  你的老大
But when you get caught, will your boss even think twice
杀你灭口之前会有一点点犹豫吗
before killing you to cover his tracks?
顺便问一句  你老大是谁啊
Who is your boss, by the way?
我们要不要打开账本看一下
Should we open that ledger and find out?
这应该表示"无可奉告"
Guess that's a "No comment."
纽约警察  放下武器
NYPD! Drop your weapon!
联调局  我们在执行公务
FBI! We're here on official business.
安吉拉斯女士是一宗谋杀案的目击证人
Ms. Angelis is a witness in a homicide investigation.
放下枪
Drop your guns!
你听见警笛声了吗  皮特
You hear sirens, Pitt?
两个纽约警局的警探
Two NYPD detectives just took a hot door
没有支援就冲了过来
without calling for backup.
你们也不是执行公务来的
You're not here on official business either.
格里芬在哪里  格里芬在哪里  格里芬在哪里
Where's Griffin? Where's Griffin? Where's Griffin?
沃克
Walker.
沃克是HR的老大
调度  我需要一辆车
Dispatch, I need a bus.
抓到一个肩部中枪的嫌犯
Got a suspect in custody with a GSW to his shoulder.
我错过了什么
What did I miss?
详情尽在明天的报纸上
Nothing you can't read in tomorrow's paper.
抱歉  女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
我们需要那个作为证据
We're gonna need that as evidence.
谢谢你
Thank you.
西蒙斯
弗斯科
之后  我们在中城区有个募集活动
So after that, we've got the fundraiser in midtown,
我们要在三点前赶到
and then we have to get there by 3:00.
能做到吗
Can we do that?
兰登・沃克
Landon Walker!
你因受贿罪
You're under arrest for receiving bribes,
企业腐败罪和同谋罪被捕
enterprise corruption, and conspiracy.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的一切都将
Anything you say can and will be used
成为呈堂证供
against you in a court of law.
HR嫌疑人：沃克接受调查
那么
So...
你脱身了  老大被关起来了
you're off the hook. The boss is locked up.
我们两清了吧
Are we done here?
一旦进来  永远别想退出
Once you're in, you're never out.
你还想要我做什么
You want anything else from me...
不许再提我的孩子
never mention my kid again.
我不是你儿子的威胁  莱奈尔
I'm not a threat to your son, Lionel.
你才是
You are.
没有尸体  没有子弹
No bodies, no bullets.
你平常的约会是这样的啊
So this is what a normal date with you is like.
不错  对吧
Nice, isn't it?
不过这恐怕是最后一次了
And I'm afraid it has to be our last.
我喜欢你  约翰
I like you, John.
还挺喜欢的
Quite a bit actually.
但是我已经嫁给工作了
But I'm married to my work.
老实说  我觉得你心里还有点记挂
And honestly, I still think you're a little hung up
佐伊・摩根
on Zoe Morgan.
回见
See ya.
那你放弃追踪西装男了吗
So you're off to chase your man in the suit?
不  你是对的  都市传奇
No, you were right. Urban legend.
就我这一周的经历来说
And with the week I just had,
如果真有这么一个人
if there really was a man like that,
我应该已经见到他了
I think I'd have met him by now.
里瑟先生  似乎还没结束
Mr. Reese, this may not be over.
你太偏执  芬奇
You're paranoid, Finch.
即使如此
Be that as it may...
仍觉得我们没抓对人
don't think we got the right guy.
沃克在HR的贿赂名单上
Walker was on HR's payroll.
他有害死桑布拉诺的动机
He'd have motive to want Zambrano dead.
是的  是的  绝对是他雇佣了
Yes, yes, and he definitely hired
皮特和博格尔去杀玛克辛
Pitt and Bogle to hunt down Maxine,
就是这点让我很疑惑
but that's what troubles me.
HR的头儿非常聪明  不像会雇佣
The head of HR is brilliant, not the type to hire
两个失败的联邦探员去谋杀一位记者
a pair of washed up feds to gun down a reporter.
沃克  我不觉得他有足够的头脑
And Walker-- I'm not convinced he has the cunning
和人脉策划如此复杂的事件
or the connections to mastermind something this complicated.
好吧
All right.
如果沃克不是HR真正的头儿
If Walker isn't the real head of HR,
那谁是
who is?
即时新闻
格里芬以绝对优势获得胜利
纽约市民做出了选择
The people of New York have spoken,
我很荣幸能成为下一任市长
and I'm proud to be your next mayor.
即时新闻
格里芬以绝对优势获得胜利
原来沃克也在贿赂名单上
So you had Walker on the payroll too, huh?
两面下注
Hedging your bets.
英明
Smart.
提醒我永远别背叛你  老大
Remind me never to cross you, boss.
所以我的名字绝不会出现在贿赂名单上
That's why I never put my name on the payroll.
手握实权  谁还需要金钱
Who needs money when you have real power?
流水的政客  铁打的我们
The politicians come and go, but we'll be here forever.